BUSINESS PLANNER AND PRODUCT MANAGER

Summary

An experienced product manager with extensive experience in engineering, pre-sales support, technical marketing and applications engineering; an MBA student at UC Berkeley; a highly organized, detail-oriented, and conscientious self-starter, able to strategize and prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks with creativity, enthusiasm and humor.

Highlights

Vice-President Intel Employee Resource Group. *Bhangra Expert (Traditional Indian Folk Dance) dancer and teacher, teach Bhangra at gym to young children, encouraging them to adopt dancing as part of their physical fitness routines. *Punjabi and Hindi Language Instructor.

Experience

Business Planner and Product Manager 07/2015 to Current

Netapp Charlotte, NC

- Responsible for setting and executing product strategies and for managing supply across Intel Micro-server verticals.
- Uniquely positioned as an influencer to be the voice of Business unit to the factory and the voice of the factory to the BU.
- Driving product supply strategy determination & execution direction with cross platform groups for new product introduction, end of life of older products, and road-map SKU offerings.
- Determining and Managing geo/customer allocation through monthly, weekly and out-of-cycle processes and establishing monthly build strategies at the family and vertical level.
- Proactively managing inventory, supply constraints and build strategies with attention to tactical capacity planning.
- Owning supply messaging and VMI hub guidance for the product line and determining appropriate hub loading and monitoring strategy and drive the supply chain accordingly.

Technical Marketing Engineer 12/2014 to 07/2015

Analog Devices, Inc. Camas, WA

- for PC client products.
- Setup and executed TME strategies for key Intel Products and doing Customer design reviews.
- Worked with technologists and other area experts to help resolve customer questions and concerns.
- Provided technical support to the FAE's.

Sr. Design and implementation Engineer 01/2011 to 01/2014

Cisco Systems, Inc. Providence, RI

- Promoted to senior member of the Intel Xeon Phi CPU design team responsible for designs used in supercomputers.
- Working as a first line of support for show stopper issues.
- Lead decision maker on highly ambiguous design project deliverables; initiated and executed timely resolutions which reduced the risk to projected schedule by almost 25%.
- Mentoring engineers on caveats of design flow, facilitating efficient execution and a lower design bug rate.
- Defined and drove design methodology for hardware server chip designs and influenced senior management adoption on several critical methodology changes, resulting in 10-15% faster runtime on all design flows.
- Owned pieces of chipset design and ensured timely execution from design planning to manufacturing of Intel Atom based micro server designs.
- Trained a team of 10 junior and senior designers on constant updates in hardware design flow.
- Collaborated with cross-site and cross-functional teams in Malaysia, Arizona, Santa Clara and Oregon on technical project issues and consistently drove them to resolution.

Product Applications Engineer 01/2010 to 01/2011

XILINX INC City, STATE

- Provided project support for key Tier-1 customer accounts, resulting in successful completion of client projects and helped build client's confidence in Xilinx Sales and Support Services.
- Responsible for direct intra-departmental and inter-departmental communication between engineering, management and marketing teams, resulting in an efficient and timely resolution of customer as well as internal issues.
- Authored customer-visible answer records providing workarounds and information on design issues published externally on the web as well as Xilinx knowledge base resulting in fewer than 5 customer escalations per month.

Technical Solutions Specialist 01/2007 to 01/2010

RICOH AMERICAS CORPORATION City, STATE

- Field Applications and Sales Support).
- Proposed and designed custom Ricoh business solutions for specific customer needs, resulting in sales-wins and an overall increase in revenue.
- Assisted customers in solving and/or managing data security, data storage and data management issues impacting their projects and/or Ricoh devices and handled customer escalations and tactical software patch requests.
- Investigated and diagnosed problems on both the Ricoh platform/services and customers' site(s), including in-depth analysis and diagnosis in the data transfer, data management and network technologies and protocols.

Co-Founder, Marketing Consultant and Social Media Content Manager 01/2008 to Current ALPHA GLOBAL ENTERPRISES City , STATE

- Alpha helps working Professionals gain a deeper insight into finer aspects of Success, Self-Exploration and Life by providing tools, presentations and trainings on personality development and soft skills required in corporate world.
- Alpha also provides coaching for key technical as well as non-technical certifications.
- Co-founded Alpha Global, helped with initial marketing as well as business plans and designed coursework which can fit specific needs of not only individuals but also private schools.
- Led an offshore marketing team of 4 to drive marketing effort to win new customers and currently providing working as an off-shore
 consultant.

Education

Master of Business Administration (MBA) 2018 HAAS SCHOOL OF BUSINESS, UC BERKELEY City, State Master of Science: Electrical Engineering 2010 SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERISTY City, State Electrical Engineering MS: EE EE

Interests

Swimming, running, hiking, camping, and traveling.

Additional Information

• Interests: Swimming, running, hiking, camping, and traveling.

Skills

Alpha, business plans, business solutions, capacity planning, coaching, hardware, consultant, CPU, client, data management, data transfer, diagnosis, direction, Driving, senior management, functional, hardware design, Hindi, hub, Instructor, Intel, inventory, Managing, marketing, Mentoring, messaging, win, network, presentations, processes, protocols, Punjabi, sales, Sales and Support, Sales Support, strategy, supply chain, teacher, technical support, TME